<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/ig/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/ig/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-03T06:55:53+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ig/</id><title type="html">ivonneg</title><subtitle>User Experience Designer</subtitle><author><name>ivonng</name></author><entry><title type="html">EventHub</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/eventhub.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EventHub" /><published>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/eventhub</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/eventhub.html">&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a city that is oversaturated with weekend events and festivals, Chicagoans need a succinct and efficient
way to access a database of information regarding these specific events. Users want to know more than just
the date and time of their favorite events and this is where EventHub comes in. The general challenge we
are addressing is the wide variety of grievances that attendees have with these kinds of events as well
as attempting to create an efficient hub of information regarding these events that will not force users
to navigate too far from their current workflow (i.e social media). These grievances include but are not
limited to: cost of event / vendor costs, accessibility by public transportation, and overcrowding
(or under-crowding). EventHub addresses these grievances by offering site-specific information about a
given festival on an easily navigated platform allowing the user to quickly decide whether this is an
event they would like to attend or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Overview and Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design goals that paved the way for most of the decisions we made were primarily based on ease of use and accessibility of specific information.
  That said, we specifically want to include information regarding breakdown / location of attendees so that users could see approximately how many people
  were at the event at a given time as well as predict roughly how many people would be there when they chose to arrive. We also wanted to include a way
  for users to gather information about vendors that would be tabling and their price breakdowns from within the app itself. We wanted these goals to be
  addressed in tandem with the desire for a location functionality that linked you to festivals that were in your area based on a programmable radius from
  the user. Our prototype will demonstrate our early iterations of how to best address these goals, which were then further developed in our design process.
  We wanted to create a streamlined process for the user that had only 1-3 screens between them and their ultimate goal no matter what the goal is.
  These early examples were clunky and not the most efficient for user experience and so in our secondary prototyping stages we fixed many issues by adding
  interactive maps earlier into the interface as well as designing multiple ways for a user to link to other pages and get back home so that no matter where
  they were they could easily navigate to a variety of other pages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To address many of our design goals, we quickly realized that an interactive map would be the necessary centerpiece of our application. This interactive
  map is our main feature and contains selectable vendor lists and locations, breakdowns of where nearby public transportation is located (including Divvy
  station breakdowns of what the ratio of Divvy Bike : Open Spot is) and a live updated map of attendee dispersal throughout the event. The map can be used
  for all basic information regarding stages of performing artists and entrances and exits, but we felt that an interactive map to this extent would centralize
  all necessary information into one easy location. Another useful feature is the ability to save events that interest you into a calendar that can send you
  notifications regarding the festival as it nears (ex. Reminders of when it is, updates to the performing artists schedules, free ticket opportunities, etc.).
  This offers value to the user because they no longer have to hold information about these events in their heads, but can rather rely on a calendar that will
  remind them as well as make them aware of opportunities that surround the event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As two people who transferred into this major a bit later than some others, it was scary to try and find internships without having as competitive of portfolios
  as other peers in our class and grade since they had several quarters of experience over us. However, this designing process allowed us to create something that
  is portfolio-ready. Although further revision is necessary, we feel comfortable showing employers a prototype that is higher fidelity prototype than what we have
  built in previous courses. It is apparent that we still have a ways to go, but now employers can track our growth as designers and this assignment shows our
  capabilities and potential more than any work we have completed thus far. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assignment was helpful, but could have benefited from a more complex usability testing element. Perhaps we could have done more usability testing with harsher
  critiques in order to build our application at a more expedited rate. This was obviously due to the constraint of time, but would have nonetheless been beneficial
  to us as designers. If we could have looked at some more minor, visual elements, this application could have been much stronger and perhaps even more visually engaging.
	Additionally, we have had such minimal training in Axure and other prototyping software that it was difficult to simply pick up all the knowledge we needed to make our
  application interactive. Some ideas were just too complex to execute and this hindered our ability to make the application we truly wanted to make. If we could have had
  more workshops that went in-depth into many softwares, perhaps we would have been able to execute more complex features. However, we realize that this is another constraint
  of time and resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this application is something we are both proud to have created. The idea is salient to the both of us and is a pretty high-fidelity prototype. Our attempts to
  make it as interactive as possible and aesthetically pleasing surely come through. This has been one large step in the right direction for the both of us and will be a
  landmark in our journey as beginning designers and developers. Hopefully, we can build upon this application in the future and allow it evolve even after this assignment
  is submitted. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Check out EventHub here! &lt;a href=&quot;https://sketch.cloud/s/QReAw/all/page-1/home/play&quot;&gt;EventHub&lt;/a&gt;.</content><author><name>ivonng</name></author><summary type="html">Introduction</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ChicagoRuby</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/chicagoruby.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ChicagoRuby" /><published>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/chicagoruby</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ig/2018/04/17/chicagoruby.html">&lt;p&gt;Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Science cuts two ways, of course; its products can be used for both good and evil. But there's no turning back from science. The early warnings about technological dangers also come from science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was most significant about the lunar voyage was not that man set foot on the Moon but that they set eye on the earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Chinese tale tells of some men sent to harm a young girl who, upon seeing her beauty, become her protectors rather than her violators. That's how I felt seeing the Earth for the first time. I could not help but love and cherish her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who have seen the Earth from space, and for the hundreds and perhaps thousands more who will, the experience most certainly changes your perspective. The things that we share in our world are far more valuable than those which divide us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There can be no thought of finishing for ‘aiming for the stars.’ Both figuratively and literally, it is a task to occupy the generations. And no matter how much progress one makes, there is always the thrill of just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;The dreams of yesterday are the hopes of today and the reality of tomorrow. Science has not yet mastered prophecy. We predict too much for the next year and yet far too little for the next ten.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spaceflights cannot be stopped. This is not the work of any one man or even a group of men. It is a historical process which mankind is carrying out in accordance with the natural laws of human development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Designing... a lot of it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we got further and further away, it [the Earth] diminished in size. Finally it shrank to the size of a marble, the most beautiful you can imagine. That beautiful, warm, living object looked so fragile, so delicate, that if you touched it with a finger it would crumble and fall apart. Seeing this has to change a man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;img/posts/ChicagoRuby New IA.pdf&quot; alt=&quot;Info Archit&quot;&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Information Architecture&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space, the final frontier. These are the voyages of the Starship Enterprise. Its five-year mission: to explore strange new worlds, to seek out new life and new civilizations, to boldly go where no man has gone before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stand out here in the wonders of the unknown at Hadley, I sort of realize there’s a fundamental truth to our nature, Man must explore, and this is exploration at its greatest.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Going Mobile&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>ivonng</name></author><summary type="html">Never in all their history have men been able truly to conceive of the world as one: a single sphere, a globe, having the qualities of a globe, a round earth in which all the directions eventually meet, in which there is no center because every point, or none, is center — an equal earth which all men occupy as equals. The airman's earth, if free men make it, will be truly round: a globe in practice, not in theory.</summary></entry></feed>